1196 men aboard, 5 days in water, 317 survived
USS Indianapolis: Men of Courage is a action, war
film directed by Mario Van Peebles.
The harrowing true story of the crew of the USS Indianapolis, who were stranded in the Philippine
Sea for five days after delivering the atomic weapons that would eventually end WWII.
As they awaited rescue, they endured extreme thirst,
hunger, and relentless shark attacks.
Captain McVay, played by Nicolas Cage.
McWhorter, played by Tom Sizemore.
Bama, played by Matt Lanter.
Chuck Gwinn, played by Thomas Jane.
Clara, played by Emily Tennant.
Garrison, played by Craig Tate.
USS Indianapolis: Men of Courage (also titled USS Indianapolis: Disaster in the Philippine Sea) is a 2016 American war disaster film directed by Mario Van Peebles and written
by Cam Cannon and Richard Rionda Del Castro, based largely on the true story of the loss of the ship of the same name in the closing stages of World War II.
The film stars Nicolas Cage, Tom Sizemore, Thomas Jane,
Matt Lanter, Brian Presley, and Cody Walker.
Principal photography began on June 19, 2015, in Mobile, Alabama.
The film premiered in the Philippines on August 24, 2016.
It was released as a digital rental on iTunes and Amazon in the United States on
October 14, 2016, and in limited theaters during the Veterans Day weekend.
The film underperformed at the box office and
received negative reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of world war ii, based on true story, 1940s.